# DAMJAN KOLEVSKI

## Product Design Engineer

+389 70 277 552
damjan.kolevski@gmail.com
damjankol.github.io/portfolio



with a bachelor's degree of Mechanical Engineering in Industrial Design, and five years of experience in the field. Recently he mastered an academy of UX Design, and is working in the IT Industry, on a software for Smart Manufacturing/Industry 4.0.

His strongest professional competences are: Research, Front End Programming, New product development, CAD, Mechanical Engineering, Project management, Developing department procedures, Design and execution of Manufacturing Technologies, Continuous improvement (Kaizen), LEAN culture (5S, Kanban), On-time results, International teamwork, Dynamic workflow.

Industries he experiences: IT, Healthcare, Smart Manufacturing, Sport, Hospitality.

Personally, he is described as: committed, honest, reliable, enthusiastic, creative, details-oriented, communicative, adaptable, patient, tolerant.



## DIGITAL COMPETENCE

- Adobe XD, Figma, InVision, Miro (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- Photoshop, Illustrator (Graphic Design)
- HTML, CSS, JS (Front End Programming)
- Solidworks, AutoCAD, MAYA, CATIA
   (3D assembly modelling & 2D technical drawing)
- ProCast, Matlab, Adams (Dynamic simulations)
- 3ds MAX (Animation)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **UX Design Engineer**

ATS GLOBAL, Industry: IT, Smart Manufacturing Apr. 2021 - Present, Skopje

- User Researching, User Tests (with Userlytics)
- Mapping User Flows (with Miro)
- Designing Wireframes (with InVision)
- Designing Prototypes (with Figma)
- Implementing Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)
- Planning a development of Design System
- Working in Agile environment (with Azure DevOps)

## R&D / CAD Mechanical Engineer

CRANFIELD FOUNDRY, Industry: Foundry Jan. 2019 - Sep. 2020, Probishtip

## **Development Engineer**

CASTINVEST, Industry: Foundry Feb. 2018 - Oct. 2018, Skopje

#### **Business Developer**

REGEMAT 3D, Industry: Healthcare Aug. 2017 - Jan. 2018, Granada

#### **Assistant to CEO**

KOPLAST, Industry: Plastic Mar. 2015 – Jul. 2017, Skopje

### **Graphic Designer & Events Organizer**

Macedonian Canoe Federation, Industry: Sport Mar. 2014 – present (part-time), Skopje

## **EDUCATION**

## **BRAINSTER Academy of UX/UI Design**

Jul. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Pre-program/Graphic Design (Photoshop, Illustrator)
- Fundamentals of UX/UI Design
- Tools: AdobeXD, Figma, InVision (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- Design Systems, Responsive Design
- Front End Programming (HTML, CSS, JS)
- Storytelling, Pitching

## MOTIVA Management Training

Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2013

Communication Skills; Developing and Managing Effective Teams; Entrepreneurship, Developing SMEs, Writing Business Plan; Financial Mgmt.; Leadership and Business Negotiation; Strategic Mgmt. and Business Ethics; Export Marketing; Presentation Skills; Change Mgmt.; Human Resources Mgmt.; Quality Mgmt.

## University Ss. Cyril & Methodius in Skopje, Bachelor of Mech. Engineering in Industrial Design

Sep. 2011 - Jan. 2015

- Mechanical Engineering,
- New Product Development,
- 3D assembly modelling & 2D technical drawing (Solidworks, AutoCAD, MAYA, CATIA),
- Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing,
   Design for Manufacturability, Material Properties
- Graphic Design (Photoshop),
- Dynamic Simulation (Matlab, Adams),
- Animation (3ds MAX),
- Web Design/HTML/CSS (Dreamweaver)

#### **Vocational Courses**

- IBM: Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner (August 2021)
- IDF: User Research Methods and Best Practices (July 2021)
- IDF: Conducting Usability Testing (June 2021)

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

- age: Millennial
- languages: English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate), French (beginner), Macedonian (mother tongue) Bulgarian (fluent), Croatian (fluent), Serbian (fluent).
- driver's license: B category (active driver)
- hobbies: Painting, Photography, Architecture, Folklore, Ecology, Humanitarian Volunteering, Tennis, Skiing, Volleyball, Hiking, White-water kayaking, Karate, Scouting, Dancing, Ice-skating, Table-tennis, Billiard, Ultimate Frisbee, Playing Piano, Flute...